Well good afternoon everybody welcome
大家下午好，欢迎大家
Good to see you
很高兴见到你
So this week we're going to study how to incorporate concurrency into programs
所以本周我们将研究如何将并发纳入程序
Now we've seen concurrency before in the form of processes exception handlers
现在我们以流程异常处理程序的形式看到了并发
And in the case of processes it was a mechanism
在进程的情况下，它是一个机制
We use the processes as a mechanism to run multiple independent application programs
我们使用进程作为运行多个独立应用程序的机制
Now but you could concurrency also exists in application programs
现在的话，并行也可以存在于应用程序中
Now we've seen a little bit of this when we studied signal handlers
现在，当我们研究信号处理程序时，我们已经看到了一点点
Okay so a signal handler is a concurrent flow that runs concurrently with your main application program
好的，所以信号处理程序是一个与主应用程序同时运行的并发流
Okay and we've seen
好的，我们已经看到了
We've seen how some of the difficulties that can arise
我们已经看到了可能出现的一些困难
When we introduce concurrency in our programs
当我们在程序中引入并发时
So even with something like a signal handler which isn't doing very much
所以即使是像信号处理程序这样的东西也做得不多
It's very hard for us to reason about this kind of thing we have two concurrent flows running at the same time
我们很难推断出我们同时运行两个并发流的这种事情
Like these our brains just tend to be kind of sequential we want to think about things happening one after the other
就像我们大脑的思考往往是有序的，我们是一件件的思考发生的事情的
You know it is and it's much easier for us to reason about that
你们知道的，我们更容易理解这一点
Reasoning about multiple things happening at the same time really causes problems
关于同时发生多件事的推理确实会引起问题
And the fundamental reason is that to really reason about say (two independent) two concurrent flows
而根本原因在于真正推理说（两个独立的）两个并发流
We have to account for all of the possible inter leavings of those flows
我们必须考虑到这些流的所有可能的间隔
Okay and that's where and that's that grows exponentially with the number of flows
好吧，那就是那里和那个随着流的数量呈指数增长的地方
Okay so you had you saw this with your signal handlers when you did shell lab
好的，当你做shell实验室的时候，你已经在信号处理程序那边见识过了
You had two concurrent flows the main program and your signal handler
你有两个并行的程序流，主程序和信号处理程序
Both accessing a shared resource in the form of the jobs list
两者都以作业列表的形式访问共享资源
Right and you had to be very careful to prevent an interleaving where
对，你必须非常小心，以防止交叉
Where that data structure was being referenced in an inconsistent state
在不一致状态下引用该数据结构的位置处
So what we're going to do this week,and into next week is we're going to look at that kind of application level concurrency
那么我们这周以及下周要做的事情就是去看看应用级的并发
But in a more principled in a more principled way than we encountered with signal handlers
但是，与信号处理程序相比，我们会从更加底层的方面去研究
So as soon as you have multiple flows accessing shared resources all kinds of bad things can happen in your program
因此，只要你有多个流访问共享资源，你的程序就会发生各种糟糕的情况
And these have been...these bad things,these problems that occur been objects of study in computer science for decades
这些都是......这些糟糕的事情，这些问题几十年来一直是计算机科学研究的对象
But the kinds of things that can happen are our races
但是这种事情的发生是我们的日常
Which we've seen in when we did the shell lab
我们在进行shell实验时已经看过了
Where the outcome whether good or bad outcome depends on some some arbitrary scheduling decision
结果的好坏取决于一些任意的调度决策
Right in the case of you know one of the races we saw
在我们之前遇到过的情况中
In the case of a shell was the case where that a child just because of a scheduling decision by the kernel
在shell的情况下，就只是因为内核的调度决定的子程序
Runs and finishes before the parent has a chance to add that child to the job list
在父程序有机会将该子程序添加到工作列表之前运行并完成
Okay so that's a classic example of a race
好的，这是一个典型的例子
And similarly if you have two people that are trying to making accessing a reservation system on a bird for an airline
同样，如果两个人试图同时访问航空公司的订票系统
Who gets the if they both access at the same time,who actually gets a seat
谁将会订购成功？谁将会获得一个席位？
Just depends on those various scheduling decisions that are going on in the reservation system
仅取决于预订系统中正在进行的各种调度决策
Another kind of a problem that occurs is deadlock
另一种发生的问题是死锁
So a deadlock is a condition
所以僵局是一个条件
That exists where you have multiple flows waiting for an event that will never occur
存在这样的情况，即你有多个流等待永远不会发生的事件
Okay so using printf in a signal handler is an example of this kind of problem
好的，所以在信号处理程序中使用printf就是这种问题的一个例子
Introduces the potential for that kind of problem
介绍这种问题的可能性
Okay so in your main routine you execute a printf
好的，在你的主程序中执行printf
And that printf acquires a lock on some system resource,i think it's a terminal lock
而且printf获取了对某些系统资源的锁定，我认为这是一个终端锁定
And then after that main printf
然后在那个主要的printf之后
Acquires that lock it gets interrupted by a signal handler
获取锁定它被信号处理程序中断
And now the signal handler if it does a printf
现在是信号处理程序，如果它执行printf
That printf will try to acquire that lock
那个printf会试图获得那个锁
But it won't be able to get it because the printf and the main routine has it
但它无法得到它，因为printf和主程序都有它
So now your signal handler the printf and the signal handler is waiting for the event will never occur
所以现在你的信号处理程序的printf正在等待一个永远不会发生的事件
It's waiting for that lock to be released
等待释放的锁
And it will never occur because the printf in the main routine can't release the lock
它永远不会发生，因为主程序中的printf不会释放锁定
Until the signal handler returns
直到信号处理程序返回
And the signal handler can't acquire the lock until the printf in the main routine terminates
并且在主程序中的printf终止之前，信号处理程序无法获取锁定
So that's a classic example of deadlock
所以这是一个典型的死锁示例
Another more from real life imagine that you're all drivers follow the rules very precisely
再举一个生活中的例子，想象一下你们都是司机，并且非常遵守规则
And the rule for a four-way stop is that whoever gets there first gets to go first okay
四方停留的规则是，首先到达那里的人可以先行
So if four cars arrive at the intersection exactly the same time
因此，如果四辆汽车完全同时到达交叉路口
Then you have a deadlock,you have none of the drivers was first
然后你就陷入了死锁，无法确定哪个司机先行
So none of the drivers goes
所以没有一个司机会走
And so they're all waiting for a condition that will never occur
所以他们都在等待一个永远不会发生的情况
And then other classical things that can go wrong or things like liveness  starvation fairness of this
还有一些其他的经典的出错案例案例，像活体饥饿的公平性
Starvation occurs when you fail
当你失败时会发生饥饿
You're trying to do something but you fail to make progress because somebody else keeps getting all the work
你正试图做一些事情，但你没有取得进展，因为其他人不断得到所有的工作
Right so if you were...if you had two processes and the kernel always scheduled process a instead of process b
是的，如果你是......如果你有两个进程并且内核总是安排进程而不是进程b
Process b that would be an example of process b being starved out because of a improper scheduling decision
进程b就是一个饥饿出局的例子，因为一个不正确的调度决策
And then we would say that that that scheduling policy always schedule b is unfair
然后我们会说调度策略总是安排b是不公平的
Right so it doesn't have this property of fairness where every entity in the system gets sort of a reasonable chunk of the processor
对，所以它没有系统中的每个实体都有一个合理的处理器块的公平的特性
So like i said i mean this
就像我说的那样，我的意思是这个
Concurrency has been studied for years it's a very difficult topic
并发已经研究多年，这是一个非常困难的话题
Because of this because of this sort of exponential explosion in the number of inter leavings
正因为如此，因为这种间隔的数量呈指数级增长
So we can't,we're not going to cover all of them
所以我们不能，我们不会涵盖所有这些
But we will cover some so as you get a reasonable idea
但是，当你关于将并发加入到你的程序中有些许想法时
Of how to incorporate concurrency in your programs
我会扩展补充一些
Now for our study of application level concurrency
现在我们研究应用程序级并发
We're going to use servers as a motivating example
我们将使用服务器作为一个激励性的例子
And the reason is that you cannot write a correct server without using concurrency
原因是你在不使用并行的情况下是没有办法写一个正确的服务器的
Okay so it's a good,it's a really good,good motivation
好的，这是一个很好的，这是一个非常好的，良好的动力
And here's the reason
这就是原因
So far we've looked at servers that are iterative
到目前为止，我们已经研究了迭代的服务器
Okay so the only process requests from one client at a time
好的，所以一次只能来自一个客户的进程请求
And once they finish processing a request from a client then they go on to the next client
一旦他们完成处理客户的请求，他们就会继续处理下一个请求
So they so like with our iterative echo server
所以就像我们的迭代的echo 服务器
You can see the each of these clients makes a connection request
你可以看到每个客户端发出连接请求
Then it writes a line of text to the server
然后它将一行文本写入服务器
And then it waits for the server to echo that back
然后等待服务器回复
And in this case this simple case then it just closes
在这种情况下，这个简单的案例然后就会关闭
Okay and the server waits for a connection requests and accept
好的，服务器等待连接请求并接受
And then waits for...and then once it accepts that connection requests
然后等待......然后一旦它接受了连接请求
It reads and when waits for what waits for that client to write something to the connection
它读取并等待，等待该客户端向连接写入内容
And then it echoes it back
然后它回复它
And then it waits for the next line
然后它等待下一行
Until the client closes that connection
直到客户端关闭该连接
And then the server closes this connection
然后服务器关闭此连接
And then only them does it does it do another except to wait for the next connection request
做完上述操作，他才会继续等待下一个连接请求
Okay so in this example client two is also making a connection request
好的，在这个例子中，客户端2也在发出连接请求
But it never runs it has to wait until the server actually echoes back the response
但它永远不会运行，它必须等到服务器实际回应响应
Now there's a little subtlety here that  in where exactly that this client waits
现在这里有一点点微妙之处在于这个客户端究竟在哪里等待
So the semantics of connect
所以连接的语义
You would think that connect would block until the connection was established
你会认为连接会阻塞，直到建立连接
But actually if you tried this out
但实际上如果你试过这个
It turns out that connect actually initiates the connection process inside the kernel
事实证明，connect实际上启动了内核中的连接过程
But then it returns
但后来又回来了
Okay before the connection has been established
好在连接建立之前
And then it does a right
然后它做对了
And that right also returns immediately
而且这项权利也会立即回归
So right it doesn't wait until the server reads that the string that was written
所以他直到服务器读取写入的字符串才停止等待
And it doesn't block until it calls the read function waiting for the echoed response from the server
并且它不会阻塞，直到它调用read函数等待来自服务器的回显响应
So it actually it doesn't block until it hits this read and then it spends all
所以它实际上它不会阻止，直到它达到这个读函数然后它花费所有的时间
It waits waits waits waits
它等待等待等待
And finally the server accepts the connection requests and then writes  the string back to the client
最后，服务器接受连接请求，然后将字符串回送回客户端
So the call to connect actually returns immediately
所以对connect的调用实际上立即返回
And it exploits this feature in the kernel that can queue up these connection requests
它利用内核中的这个功能来排队这些连接请求
Okay so that the kernel now is going through all the process of setting up the connection
好的，现在内核正在完成设置连接的所有过程
But the application program continues
但应用程序仍在继续
And then the right,the right inside the client doesn't block
然后右边，客户端内部的权利不会阻止
Because the kernel can also queue up the data that's written
因为内核也可以排队写入的数据
So it'll little queue it up remember that it was written when the connection actually gets created
所以它很少排队，记住它是在连接实际创建时写的
Then it'll send that data along
然后它会发送数据
And
和
But there's no way to avoid the read from blocking,write a read can't return until it gets some data
但是没有办法避免读取阻塞，写入读函数只有接收到数据才会返回
Okay so read has to block
好的，所以读函数就会阻塞
Okay now here's the fundamental flaw of an iterative server
好的，这就是迭代服务器的根本缺陷
And the reason why we have to write them with the concurrency
我们必须用并发性来编写它们的原因
Okay so let's say in a echo server example
好吧，让我们在echo服务器示例中说
We have a client that creates a connection
我们有一个创建连接的客户端
Or request a connection it's accepted in the server
或者请求一个被服务器接受的链接
Does the write
写的
The server echoes back one you know one string
服务器回显一个，你知道的，一个字符串
And then the client blocks again or instead of doing the next write or closing the connection
然后客户端再次阻塞或代替执行下一次写入或关闭连接
The person
此人
The user goes out to lunch and never types in a string to the the echo client
用户外出吃午餐，从不输入字符串到echo客户端
Okay so at this point the server calls read
好的，所以此时服务器调用read
And then it blocks waiting for this user to type in something
然后它会锁柱，等待该用户输入内容
And so that the client can send it to the server to be echoed
这样客户端就可以将其发送到服务器进行回显
But the user is gone gets hit by a truck
但是用户已经离开
Who knows
谁知道
Anyway so this never this read then blocks
无论如何所以这从来没有读过那么块
For an indeterminate amount of time right
对于一段不确定的时间吧
And while it's blocking client to which also wants service
并且与此同时，他阻止其他想要服务器服务的客户端
It has to block
它必须阻止
Okay so now you're in an untenable situation
好的，现在你处于一种难以为继的境地
Where one client has sort of totally affected
一个客户完全受影响的地方
All of the other clients in the system and none of the other clients can get service
系统中的所有其他客户端都不能获得服务
It's so if this were a web server
如果这是一个Web服务器就是这样
If one client for some reason
如果一个客户出于某种原因
Blocked
阻止
No other users would be able to use that web service or look at pages on that's site
没有其他用户可以使用该Web服务或查看该网站上的页面
So obviously this we can't have this
显然，我们不能这么搞
Okay so the solution is to use is to write a concurrent server instead of an iterative server
好的，所以解决方案是使用是编写并发服务器而不是迭代服务器
Where we'll have a separate concurrent flow handle each clients request and interact with each client
对于每一个客户请求我们都有一个独立的并发流去处理，能和每一个客户端通信
So now if one client for some reason is slow or misbehaves or blocks the system
所以现在如果一个客户因某种原因卡顿或行为不当或阻止系统
Other clients won't be affected because those clients will be handled way by concurrent flows
其他客户端不会受到影响，因为这些客户端将由并发流处理
So there are several ways a number of ways to create these.yes
所以有很多方法去创建他们
[student speaking]
It actually could and in fact that's that's a form of concurrency
它实际上可能并且事实上这是一种并发形式
So the question is the could the server queue up requests from the from clients
所以问题是服务器会对来自客户端的请求排队处理
It could but it would...
它可以，但它会......
You know i guess actually it would have to queue up it would somehow have to accept those connections right
你知道我猜它实际上必须排队它会以某种方式必须接受这些连接
So that
以便
Now so that wouldn't work so somehow you have
现在这样就行不通，所以不管怎么说
Since the accept calls are iterative sequential
由于接受调用是迭代顺序的
There's no way to get data from those other clients
无法从其他客户端获取数据
Okay but actually what you're suggesting is very similar to something called an event-based server
好的，但实际上你所建议的与基于事件的服务器非常相似
That will which is one of the ways we can create concurrent flows
那将是我们创建并发流的方法之一
So there's three ways to create these concurrent flows
因此有三种方法可以创建这些并发流
One is to use processes okay like we've already seen
一个是像我们已经看到的那样使用进程
Okay so the kernel...so in this case the kernel handles all the scheduling for us and interleaves
好的，所以内核......所以在这种情况下，内核为我们处理所有的调度
It interleaves the process execution automatically for us
它为我们自动交错的执行进程为我们
And then as we saw before each flow has its own private address space
然后正如之前看到的那样，每个流都有它自己私有的地址空间
So that each flow is independent and scheduled by the kernel
这样每个流都是独立的，并由内核调度
Okay now there's a another approach called event based
好的，现在还有一种叫做基于事件的方法
Where the programmer manually interleaves the flows
程序员手动交错流程的地方
Okay so instead of relying on the kernel to interleave these different flows
所以不需要依赖内核来交错这些不同的流程
The user the programmer creates this flows and then manually interleaves them okay
程序员创建这些流进程，然后手动分开它们
And since it's one program
因为它是一个程序
All of the flows share the same address space right
所有流都共享相同的地址空间
So they have access to all the same global data structures
因此，他们可以访问所有相同的全局数据结构
And they do they do this inter interleaving using a technique called i/o multiplexing
并且他们使用称为i / o复用的技术进行交错
You know i'll talk briefly about that but
你知道我会简单地谈谈这个问题但是
It's addressed much more detail in your book
它在你的书中提到了更多细节
The third approach which is kind of a hybrid of process based and event based is thread base
第三种方法是基于流程和基于事件的混合，是基于线程的
So used each of these flows is implemented using something called a thread
因此，使用称为线程的东西来实现这些流
The kernel like processes
内核就像进程一样
The kernel automatically interleaves these different threads
内核自动分开这些不同的线程
But unlike a process each thread shares the same address space
但与进程不同，每个线程共享相同的地址空间
Okay so each thread has access to all the global variables declared in the program
好的，所以每个线程都可以访问程序中声明的所有全局变量
So in so it's like process based and that the kernel automatically schedules it for us
因此，它就像基于进程一样，内核会自动为我们处理他
But it's like event based in the sense that
在某种意义上，他很像基于事件的
Every flow shares the same address space
每个流共享相同的地址空间
Okay so we'll look,let's look at all three of these approaches in more detail
好的，我们来看看，让我们更详细地看一下这三种方法
So the first approach is to create these flows using processes
因此，第一种方法是使用流程创建这些流
So in this case
所以在这种情况下
This is our echo server example
这是我们的echo服务器示例
The the client requests a connection
客户端请求连接
And then calls fgets to wait for the user to type something at the keyboard
然后调用fgets等待用户在键盘上输入内容
But the user is gone and so fgets this client just blocks in the call to fgets
但是用户已经离开，所以fgets这个客户端只是阻止了对fgets的调用
So the server when it gets a request,it accepts the connection requests and returns from the accept call
所以当服务器收到请求时，它接受连接请求并从accept调用返回
And after it returns from the accept call
从接受调用返回后
It forks a child
它生成一个子进程
And then that child interacts
然后那个子进程和客户端通信
That child process now will be responsible for interacting with client number one
该子进程现在将负责与第一个客户进行交互
So the child blocks waiting for data from client one
因此，孩子阻止等待来自客户端1的数据
Which is never going to show up because the the user left
由于用户离开，这永远不会出现
Okay but it that's okay because it doesn't stop the server
好的，但这没关系，因为它不会停止服务器
The server after it forks the child goes right back and calls accept
服务器在复制一个子进程后返回并继续等待连接请求
And now accept can accept the connection request from client 2
现在服务器可以接受来自客户端2的连接请求
And fork off another a different child that can interact with client 2
并复制另一个子进程同客户端2进行交互
So that child will read waits for data to show up from the client  and then it echoes it back
这样该子进程就会读取等待数据从客户端显示出来，然后再对其回复
And at some point then closes the this connection
然后在某个时候关闭这个连接
Okay so you see that this misbehaving client number one
好的，所以你看到这个未知行为的第一个客户端
Now because we have concurrent flows interacting with all the clients
现在因为我们有并发流与所有客户端交互
This misbehaving client can't adversely affect other clients
这个行为不端的客户不会对其他客户产生不利影响
Okay so now that's
好的，现在就是这样
And this idea of creating concurrent flows to interact with clients is fundamental
创建并发流以与客户交互的这种想法是至关重要的
There you have to do this in order to have a sort of a working server implementation
你必须这样做才能拥有一种有效的服务器实现
Alright so how would we actually program this process based concurrent server
好吧那么我们如何实际编程这个基于并发服务器的进程
It's actually surprisingly compact
它实际上非常紧凑
So
所以
We're going to pass in argv,we're going to pass in a port number that we want this server to listen on
我们将传入argv，我们将传入一个我们希望该服务器监听的端口号
We've got a listening descriptor and a connected descriptor
我们有一个监听描述符和一个连接的描述符
We've got and then we've got a length and an address field
我们有，然后我们有一个长度和一个地址字段
And the address is declared in a protocol independent way using this sockaddr_storage type
并且使用sockaddr_storage类型使得该地址被声明成协议无关的
Which is guaranteed to be big enough as you saw last time
如上次所见，这保证足够大
It's guaranteed to be big enough to handle any type of address either ipv4 or ipv6
它保证足够大，可以处理任何类型的地址，无论是ipv4还是ipv6
Okay so we install a sigchld_handler
好的，我们安装了一个sigchld_handler
And then we use the open_listenfd call from your textbook
然后我们使用教科书中的open_listenfd调用
To create a listening descriptor on port that we pass in as the as the argument to this program
为了在端口上创建一个监听描述符，并传入一个参数
And then the server goes into an into a loop
然后服务器进入一个循环
And in each iteration
并在每次迭代中
It gets the size of the socketaddr_storage type and puts it into clientlen
它获取socketaddr_storage类型的大小并将其放入clientlen
And then it calls it except
然后它调用它除外
With pointers to the clients address and clientlen
使用指针指向客户端地址和clientlen
Using the listening descriptor that was returned by open listenfd
使用由open _listenfd函数返回的侦听描述符
The accept call after it gets a connection request it returns with the address of the client that made the that
在获得连接请求之后的accept调用，它返回了生成该请求的客户端的地址
At the other end of the connection along with the true length of that  address
在连接的另一端以及该地址的真实长度
So the case of ipv4 before 4 bytes
所以ipv4的情况在4个字节之前
And then the acceptor turns this this connected file descriptor
然后接受器将此连接文件描述符转换为此
That the then that that the the child
那就是那个孩子
That that it can use to to read and write and interact with that client
它可以用来读取和写入该客户端并与之交互
So it creates say it forks the child
所以它创造了说它分叉孩子
And then the child closes it's listening descriptor
然后孩子关闭它的监听描述符
And then it calls the echo routine to interact with the client
然后它调用echo例程与客户端进行交互
And when the echo routine returns the client closes this connected descriptor and then exits
当echo例程返回时，客户端关闭此连接的描述符然后退出
And so this close isn't absolutely necessary but we just did it to be careful
因此，这种关闭并非绝对必要，但我们只是要小心谨慎
Okay now the parent
好的，现在是父母
And this is important closes the connected descriptor
这很重要，关闭连接的描述符
Because it's not going to use that connected descriptor only the child's will use that connected descriptor
因为它不会使用那个已连接的描述符，所以只有孩子会使用那个连接的描述符
So in order to avoid this memory leak it's very important for the child to to close this descriptor
因此，为了避免内存泄漏的情况，子进程关闭这个描述符非常重要
Okay because remember this the server's running in an infinite loop on it
好的，记住这个服务器在它上面是无限循环的运行的
In theory it would never terminate
理论上它永远不会终止
Okay and then to avoid a memory leak
好的，然后避免内存泄漏
We have to...in a handler we have to have a sigchld_handler that will reap all of the children that have terminated
我们必须......在一个处理程序中我们必须有一个sigchld_handler来接收所有已经终止的子进程
Okay so let's look a little more detail how this except works
好的，让我们看一下这个除了有效运行之外的更多细节
So you have a client with a client file descriptor
所以你有一个带有客户端文件描述符的客户端
And then you have a server that creates a listening descriptor
然后你有一个能够创建一个监听描述符的服务器
So let's say that's you know descriptors are indexed by small integers
所以，让我们说，你知道的，描述符是由小的整数索引的
So let's say that index is three the description number is three
所以，我们这里的索引是3，也就是描述数字是三
So the server blocks and accept waiting for this connection request
因此服务器锁住并接受等待此连接请求
The client makes a connection request using the connect call
客户端通过连接函数发送一个连接请求
Okay the server accepts the connect call and then it creates a child
好的，服务器接受connect调用，然后创建一个子节点
And then the child interacts with the client using the connected file descriptor that was returned from the accept
然后，子进程使用从accept返回的连接文件描述符与客户端进行交互
So that would be say descriptive number four just be some different number
因此，我们这里的描述数字是4，一个有些不同的数字
Okay so are the execution model we have for these process based servers
好的，我们为这些基于流程的服务器提供了执行模型
Is that we have this the server processor listening for connection requests one after the other from clients
是否我们有这个服务器的处理器能够一个接一个地监听来自客户端的连接请求
And then we have multiple clients interacting concurrently with multiple children interacting concurrently with multiple clients
然后我们有多个客户端与多个子节点并行的进行交互，而这些子节点也并行的同多个客户端交互
Okay since each of these children are processes there's no shared state between them
好的，因为这些子节点都是进程，所以他们之间没有共享状态
And both parent and child inherit,they inherit the descriptor table
并且父进程和子进程都继承了描述符表
So they have they both have copies of listenfd and listening descriptor in the connected descriptor
所以他们在连接的描述符中都有listenfd和listen描述符的副本
Okay and as we saw before the parent must close
好的，正如我们在父进程必须关闭之前看到的那样
It's copy of the connected file descriptor,the child should close the listening descriptor but
它是连接文件描述符的副本，孩子应该关闭监听描述符
It's you know just to be just because it's not needed
你知道这只是因为它不需要
All right when you,so these are actually pretty simple to create and there's just a couple of things you have to keep in mind
好的，所以这些实际上很容易创建并且你必须记住几件事
When you build a process based server
构建基于进程的服务器时
So firstly as we...as with any process that creates children
首先，我们......就像创造孩子进程的任何进程一样
It has to reap these children that have terminated to avoid this memory leak
它必须收回这些已经终止的孩子，以避免这种内存泄漏
The parent process has to close its copy of the connected file descriptor
父进程必须关闭其连接文件描述符的副本
And there's a couple reasons
而且有几个原因
in fact if it doesn't it will not only create a memory leak but that
事实上，如果不这样做，它不仅会造成内存泄漏，而且
The state associated with that descriptor will actually stay around forever
与该描述符相关联的状态实际上将永远存在
Because the kernel won't close that connection
因为内核不会关闭该连接
So it as we saw when we looked at file i/o
正如我们在查看文件i / o时看到的那样
This is just enough,this is the same kind of file i/o we looked at before
这就足够了，这是我们之前看过的同类文件i / o
So the kernel keeps a reference count for each socket that's open
因此内核为每个打开的套接字保留一个引用的计数
So after the fork now there's two,there's a parent and the child which are accessing
所以在fork之后就出现了两个，父进程和子进程，他们都能够访问
The file table associated with the connected file descriptor
与连接的文件描述符关联的文件表
Okay so that
好的，那样
And the connection won't be closed until the reference count for that connected file description is zero right
并且在连接的文件描述的引用计数为零之前，连接将不会关闭
That file table entry won't be removed from the kernel
该文件表条目不会从内核中删除
Until until there's only there until there's zero references to it
直到那里只有零参考数
Okay so both the parent and the child have to close that descriptor
好的，所以父母和孩子都必须关闭该描述符
Okay now the good thing about process based servers is that they do the job for us that we asked them to do
好的，现在基于流程的服务器的好处在于它们为我们做了我们要求他们做的工作
Right we wanted them to handle to interact with multiple clients concurrently or have that ability
我们希望他们能够同时处理多个客户端或具有这种能力
There's a very clean sharing model
有一个非常干净的共享模型
Right so there's private address spaces between the all of the children and the parent
是的，所有孩子和父母之间都有私人地址空间
They shared,they have separate descriptors,but they share they have separate copies of the descriptor table
他们共享，他们有单独的描述符副本
But they share the same open file table
但是它们共享相同的打开文件表
Okay
好的
And there's so in some sense this is a simplest possible way to create a concurrent servers
从某种意义上说，这是创建并发服务器的最简单可行的方法
And if you can get
如果你能得到
If you can get by with not sharing any global variables or sharing address basis then this is the way to go
如果你可以不共享任何全局变量或共享地址，那么这就是你的一个方法
The disadvantage is that there's additional overhead for
缺点是有额外的开销
Even with this processes copy-on-write trick that we saw for sharing the
即使我们看到读写的这个过程
Sharing the address space between the parent and the child still
在父母和孩子之间共享地址空间
It's still non-trivial overhead
这仍然是不小的开销
And it's you have to actually do a lot of work if you want to share data between processes
如果你想在进程之间共享数据，你必须做一些工作
So like let's say you want to have some kind of a shared cache between multiple processes
所以就像让我们说你想在多个进程之间拥有某种共享缓存一样
Either have to use files okay on disk
要么必须在磁盘上使用文件
Or if you want to share memory you have to use  some kind of you have to use some kind of memory mapping
或者如果你想共享内存，你必须使用某种内存映射
Or you have to use what's these inter process communication mechanisms which
或者你必须使用这些过程间通信机制
We haven't talked about but there's ways pipes are probably the ones you're most familiar with
我们还没有谈过，但管道可能是你最熟悉的方式
So a pipe allows one process to send data to another process
管道允许一个进程将数据发送到另一个进程
And there's ways to share memory between processes
并且可以在进程之间共享内存
But they're cumbersome and require i have to be implemented with care
但它们很麻烦，要求我必须谨慎实施
Okay now the second approach is we call an event-based server
好的，现在第二种方法是调用基于事件的服务器
So the idea here is that the server maintains a set of active connections
所以这里的想法是服务器维护一组活动连接
So it  has an array of of connected file descriptors from different clients okay
所以它有一系列来自不同客户端的连接文件描述符
And then it determines which of those and it also has a listening descriptor
然后它确定了哪些并且它还具有监听描述符
And then it determines which of those descriptors have pending input
然后它确定哪些描述符有待处理的输入
And it determines this using a system call called select or epoll there's several ways to determine this
它使用名为select或epoll的系统调用来确定这一点，有几种方法可以确定这一点
But basically using select or a epoll
但基本上使用选择或epoll
You can determine which of a set of descriptors has pending input right and
你可以确定哪组描述符具有待定输入权限
Then this and so the arrival of input at a descriptors is called an event because it changes the state of the descriptor
然后这样，所以输入到描述符的到来被称为事件，因为它改变了描述符的状态
So an event is always event in general is always some kind of state change
所以一个事件总是一般的事件总是某种状态的变化
So in this case when data arrives on a socket  that's a change in the state
所以在这种情况下，当数据到达一个状态发生变化的套接字时
So there was no data before the event after the event now there's data that the server can read
事件之后事件之前没有数据现在有服务器可以读取的数据
So if the listening descriptor has input then the server calls except to accept the connection
因此，如果监听描述符有输入，则服务器调用除了接受连接
And for all and then all connected descriptors that have pending inputs
对于所有已连接的描述符以及所有已连接的描述符
It services those it reads from those in some order
它以某种顺序为那些从那些读取的人提供服务
Okay now that the details for how to do this are described in the book
现在好了，书中描述了如何执行此操作的详细信息
But basically
但基本上
I mean the conceptually is pretty simple it's actually tricky to implement
我的意思是概念上非常简单，实现起来实际上很棘手
But the idea is that there's some set of active descriptors
但是这个想法是有一些活跃的描述符
there's some set of descriptors connected descriptors that you're using
你正在使用的一些连接描述符
That are being used right now to to interact with a client
现在正在被用来与客户进行交互
There's some that are inactive so if descriptors was closed
如果描述符被关闭，有一些就是非活跃的
Then it's no longer active right
然后它就不再活跃了
And then there's other descriptors that have never been used
然后还有其他从未使用过的描述符
So we just have this array of descriptors
所以我们只有这个描述符数组
And then we record there you know the the descriptor number for each of those connected for each of those descriptors
然后我们在那里记录你知道每个描述符连接的每个描述符的描述符号
And then using select or a epoll or some other mechanism
然后使用select或epoll或其他一些机制
We somehow determine which of those active descriptors have input
我们以某种方式确定哪些活动描述符有输入
And then we service each of those
然后我们为每个人提供服务
In the case of listenfd by calling except
在listenfd的情况下通过调用除外
In the case of these connected descriptors actually either
在这些连接的描述符的情况下实际上也是
This should be connectfd not clientfd
这应该是connectfd而不是clientfd
But in the case of these connected descriptors we read the data from them
但是在这些连接的描述符的情况下，我们从它们读取数据
And the when we read the data from each descriptor we do some work
当我们从每个描述符中读取数据时，我们会做一些工作
Okay so data arrives that a descriptor
好的，所以数据到达描述符
And then we read that data and then we do some kind of work
然后我们读取数据，然后我们做了一些工作
Maybe in the case of an echo server we echo it right back okay
也许在echo服务器的情况下，我们echo它就好了
In the case of a web server we may
对于Web服务器，我们可以
If that data was http request we might go and fetch a file from disk and return it
如果该数据是http请求，我们可能会从磁盘获取文件并将其返回
Okay but in any case we notice that the descriptor has some data
好的，但无论如何我们都注意到描述符有一些数据
We read that data and then we respond to it in some way
我们读了那些数据，然后我们以某种方式回复它
Okay so that response those multiple responses are concurrent flows
好的，那些多个响应是并发流
Okay the we're interacting with that client
好的，我们正在与该客户进行互动
We're interacting we're creating concurrent flows while concurrent flow for each client
我们正在进行交互，我们在为每个客户端创建并发流时创建并发流
And we're servicing those clients concurrently
我们同时为这些客户提供服务
Okay so even though it's a sequential program right we're not using fork or anything
好的，即使它是一个顺序程序，我们也没有使用fork或任何东西
It's just a c program straightforward c program
这其实就是一个c语言的程序
We're writing in such a way that we're creating our own concurrent flows
我们正在编写这样一种方式，即我们正在创建自己的并发流
So there's...as with any approach there's advantages and disadvantages
所以......就像任何方法一样，有优点和缺点
So the a big advantage of event based servers is that it's just
所以基于事件的服务器的一大优势就在于它
A sequoia it's one process with one address space
红杉这是一个具有一个地址空间的过程
Right so it's very easy you can use conventional debugger gdb to step through
这是非常容易的，你可以使用传统的调试器gdb来逐步完成
You can see everything you have access to everything
你可以看到你可以访问所有内容的所有内容
So in that sense they're much simpler to debug understand
所以从这个意义上说，调试理解起来要简单得多
And then there's no process or thread control overhead
然后没有进程或线程控制开销
So when we service a particular descriptor it's very...there's very little overhead right
因此，当我们为特定的描述符提供服务时，它非常......正常的开销非常小
We just the only overhead is sort of determining that descriptor has input available
我们唯一的开销就是确定描述符有可用的输入
Okay and so because of that this is the
好的因为这就是了
High performance web servers like nodejs,nginx,tornado they all use this event based approach gates
像nodejs，nginx，tornado这样的高性能Web服务器都使用这种基于事件的进程门
If you want to get over 10,000 requests per second you have to go with something like this
如果你想每秒获得超过10,000个请求，你必须使用这样的东西
Okay the disadvantage is it's much harder to more complexed
好吧，缺点是更难以复杂化
It to code up then the other processor thread based designs
它编码然后基于其他处理器线程的设计
And it's very difficult
这非常困难
So one of the hardest aspects of the writing and event based server
这是写作和基于事件的服务器中最难的一个方面
Is that you have to figure out how much work you're going to do in response to an event
那是你必须弄清楚你将要做多少工作来回应一个事件
Okay so let me give you...let's say that this server is a web server
好吧，让我告诉你......让我们说这个服务器是一个Web服务器
And you get input on one of your connected file descriptor
并且你可以在一个连接的文件描述符上获得输入
The simplest thing to do would be to then assume to read the entire http request
最简单的方法是假设读取整个http请求
And not return until you've read the entire request
在你阅读完整个请求之前不要返回
Okay so in that case the amount of work that you do in response to an event is very coarse-grained
好的，在这种情况下，你为响应事件所做的工作量非常粗糙
There's a lot of instructions because we're going to read every single line in that http request header
有很多指令，因为我们将读取该http请求标头中的每一行
But it's...so that's course that's an example of coarse grain
但它是......所以当然这是粗浅的一个例子
It's very simple because every time you get a request on a connected descriptor you just read the whole
它非常简单，因为每次在连接的描述符上获得请求时，你只需阅读整个请求
You just read the whole http request  and then send a response
你只需阅读整个http请求，然后发送响应即可
Okay so there's
好的，那就是
On the other hand it's vulnerable
另一方面，它很脆弱
Because what if a client misbehaves and doesn't send the entire http request
因为如果客户端行为不端并且没有发送整个http请求
What if it sends half of the requests
如果发送一半请求怎么办？
So if you were doing to design an event based web server you probably wouldn't want to do that
因此，如果你正在设计基于事件的Web服务器，你可能不希望这样做
Right because that a single client we would be back in the situation we were before
正确的是因为我们会回到原来的单一客户
Where a single misbehaving client could sort of shut down the whole server
如果一个行为不端的客户端可能会关闭整个服务器
So you might say well
所以你可能会说得好
I'm going to my unit of work that i do in response to a request will be to read a single line from the request
我要去我的工作单元，我做的是响应请求将从请求中读取一行
Okay so i'll read a single line and then i'll return
好的，所以我会读一行，然后我会回来
Okay so every so now we're interleaving reading single lines
好的，所以现在我们正在交错阅读单行
And once i've read the entire request then out then i'll send the response
一旦我读完整个请求然后我就会发送回复
So that's better right so a misbehaving client
所以这对一个行为不端的客户来说更好
If sending like whole text lines at a time
如果一次发送像整个文本行
Even if it stops halfway through we'll still be able to make progress in service other other clients
即使它中途停止，我们仍然可以在服务其他客户方面取得进展
So that's a finer grained approach it's better
所以这是一种更细粒度的方法，它会更好
It's probably more robust than waiting for the whole request
它可能比等待整个请求更强大
But it's still vulnerable
但它仍然很脆弱
Because the client could just send a partial line
因为客户端只能发送部分行
So now we're back
所以现在我们回来了
So really the only way to write a robust event based web server is to be able to handle partial lines
因此，编写基于强大事件的Web服务器的唯一方法是能够处理部分行
Just read when there's data available on a descriptor
只需在描述符上有可用数据时阅读
You just read whatever data is available
你只需阅读可用的任何数据
You remember how much you read
你记得你读了多少
If it's not a whole line you somehow have to remember that you have to buffer it remember it
如果它不是一个整行你必须记住你必须缓冲它记住它
So now it's getting really complicated right
所以现在它变得非常复杂了
But that's what you that's the price you pay for this low overhead sort of easier to debug kind of kind of model
但这就是你为这种低开销类型更容易调试的那种模型所付出的代价
And then another disadvantage is that you can't since it's really a sequential program right it's one c program
然后另一个缺点是你不能，因为它真的是一个顺序程序，它是一个c程序
You can't take advantage of multiple cores
你无法利用多个核心
So the only way to get sort of more performance out of something
因此，从某些方面获得更多性能的唯一方法
An event-based servers just to replicate copies of that server
基于事件的服务器只是为了复制该服务器的副本
But you can't make an individual server go faster by using multiple cores
但是，通过使用多个内核，你无法使单个服务器更快
Okay the third approach is to use threads to create these concurrent flows
好的第三种方法是使用线程来创建这些并发流
It's very similar to processes but there are some important differences
它与流程非常相似，但存在一些重要的差异
So let's look first at what we mean by a thread
那么让我们首先看一下线程的含义
So let's go back i'm going to...let's go back in and look at the traditional view of a process
所以，让我们回去......我们回过头来看一下流程的传统观点
So we think of a process as some context that's data structures in the kernel
因此，我们将流程视为内核中数据结构的上下文
Okay data that the kernel keeps about that process
好的数据，内核保留该进程
As well as this private address space which contains a stack  code and data and then the stack
以及这个包含堆栈代码和数据然后堆栈的私有地址空间
Okay and then as part of the and then the
好的，然后作为一部分，然后是
The process context consists of context that's associated with the program like the registers,condition codes,program counter,stack pointer
进程上下文包含与程序关联的上下文，如寄存器，条件代码，程序计数器，堆栈指针
And then it contains kernel context which is information in the kernel
然后它包含内核上下文，它是内核中的信息
That the kernel needs to implement this idea of a process
内核需要实现这个过程的想法
Okay so all of this data is actually stored in the kernel
好的，所有这些数据实际上都存储在内核中
But some of the data is directly associated with the program and other data is sort of
但有些数据与程序直接相关，而其他数据则有所不同
Support data that the kernel needs to implement processes
支持内核实现进程所需的数据
Okay so let's just take this picture
好吧，让我们注意这张照片
And we're just going to just move things around a little bit
而我们只是想稍微改变一下
So what i've done is i've taken the stack off of the this virtual address space
所以我所做的就是把这个虚拟地址空间从堆栈中取出来
And sort of pulled it out along with its stack pointer
有点把它和它的堆栈指针一起拉出来
And the contacts that's associated with the program
以及与该计划相关联的联系人
So the data registers the condition codes the stack pointer the program counter
因此数据寄存条件代码堆栈指针程序计数器
Okay and i've just renamed a thread context instead of program context
好的，我刚刚重命名了线程上下文而不是程序上下文
But it's the same it's the same thing
但它也是一样的
And then i'm going to call this whole thing the combination of a stack
然后我将整个事情称为堆栈的组合
And this thread context i'm gonna call that a thread
而这个线程上下文我将称之为一个线程
And then everything else remains the same
然后其他一切都保持不变
It's we have...we still have a code and data
我们有...我们仍然有代码和数据
And we have the kernel context
我们有内核上下文
Okay now by doing this sort of refactoring and just moving things around
好的，现在通过这种重构和只是移动的东西
I can now imagine so this stack isn't very much right
我现在可以想象这个堆栈不是很正确
It's so there's that,there's this,there's the stack space
就是这样，就是这样，有堆栈空间
And then there's a little bit of data here in the form of some registers and some things to be stored
然后这里有一些数据以一些寄存器的形式和一些要存储的东西
But in this is a fairly small amount of data
但这是一个相当少量的数据
Now when i really like this
现在，当我真的喜欢这个
Now i can
现在我能
I can think about there being multiple threads associated with the same process
我可以想到有多个线程与同一个进程相关联
If i just keep different set of data thread context for each thread
如果我只为每个线程保留不同的数据线程上下文集
And then a private a separate portion of the stack that's associated with that thread
然后私有一个与该线程关联的堆栈的单独部分
So now each thread shares the same code and data
所以现在每个线程共享相同的代码和数据
Same virtual address space has the same kernel context
相同的虚拟地址空间具有相同的内核上下文
Okay the same i/o structures
好的，相同的i / o结构
But now it has its own separate individual stack
但现在它有自己独立的单独堆栈
Okay so local variables things that you would store on a stack now would be would be private sort of independent
好的，那么你现在存储在堆栈上的局部变量将是私有的独立
And it has its own set of its own program counter its own stack pointer
并且它有自己的一组自己的程序计数器自己的堆栈指针
Its own set of registers and condition codes
它自己的一组寄存器和条件代码
And then the one difference is now is that each thread
然后现在的一个区别是每个线程
Instead of there's still a process id for this process that's pointed part of the kernel context
而不是这个进程的进程id仍然是内核上下文的一部分
But each thread now has its own thread id as part of its thread context
但是每个线程现在都有自己的线程id作为其线程上下文的一部分
Okay so now
好的，现在
The kernel can just treat each of these as separate flows
内核可以将每个流程视为单独的流程
Right there's a separate so it's just like a process now
这是一个独立的，所以现在就像一个过程
The kernel can remember where the each thread has its own program counter
内核可以记住每个线程在哪里有自己的程序计数器
And but they're running code out of the same
但他们正在运行相同的代码
That code the same code section in the virtual address space
该代码与虚拟地址空间中的代码段相同
So the sharing code sharing data
所以共享代码共享数据
But they have their own program counter
但他们有自己的程序计数器
So they can the kernel can provide
所以内核可以提供它们
Can create each of these threads as a separate flow of control
可以将每个线程创建为单独的控制流
That it then schedules just like it does of a process
然后它就像进程一样安排
Or in a similar way that does is a process
或者以与进程相似的方式进行
But the difference is the reason that for threads in the first place is that when the colonel wants to contact switch from one thread to another
但不同之处在于，对于线程而言，首先是当上校要联系从一个线程切换到另一个线程时
There's not that much information that has to be saved and restored
没有那么多信息需要保存和恢复
It's just a small amount of data
这只是一小部分数据
So the kernel has to save this the data thread one context
所以内核必须将数据线程保存一个上下文
In some data structure some way and then restore the context for thread 2
在某些数据结构中某种方式然后恢复线程2的上下文
But we're talking about a very low overhead kind of operation
但我们谈论的是一种非常低开销的操作
Right it doesn't have to mess around with page tables virtual address space or any other of the process context
没错，它不必乱用页表虚拟地址空间或任何其他进程上下文
So threads are luck kind of like processes
所以线程运气就像进程一样
But they're different in the sense that they share the same virtual address space
但是它们在共享相同的虚拟地址空间的意义上是不同的
And unlike processes which are created by fork
而且与fork创建的进程不同
Which creates a strict process hierarchy threads are just pools
这创建了一个严格的流程层次结构线程只是池
You can think of threads as pools of concurrent flows that access the same code and data
你可以将线程视为访问相同代码和数据的并发流池
And then the kernel is responsible for scheduling those flows
然后内核负责调度这些流
And if in a way that so each flow gets time on the processor
如果以某种方式让每个流程在处理器上获得时间
So much like processes,much like concurrent processes
与流程非常相似，就像并发流程一样
We say the two threads are concurrent
我们说这两个线程是并发的
If their flows overlap in time otherwise they're sequential so this is the exact same
如果它们的流量在时间上重叠，否则它们是连续的，所以这是完全相同的
Example that i showed you when we looked at processes
我们在查看流程时向你展示的示例
So here you have instead of three processes we have three threads running it within the same process
所以在这里你有三个进程而不是三个进程在同一进程中运行它
Thread a runs for a little bit
线程运行一点点
And then the kernel just decides to walk it out and run thread b
然后内核决定将其移出并运行线程b
So then thread b runs for a little bit and then the kernel decides to give thread c some time
所以然后线程b运行一点，然后内核决定给线程c一些时间
So it saves thread b's context restores thread c's context
因此它保存了线程b的上下文恢复线程c的上下文
And sets the pc to...the pc value
并将pc设置为... pc值
And thread c's context and so c runs and then the kernel decides to give a some time again
并且线程c的上下文因此c运行然后内核决定再给一段时间
So then a runs some more
那么再运行一些
So because thread a and b overlap in time they're running concurrently
因此，因为线程a和b在时间上重叠，所以它们同时运行
B and c don't overlap in time so they're not running concurrently
B和c在时间上不重叠，因此它们不会同时运行
But a and c are concurrent because they overlap in time
但是a和c是并发的，因为它们在时间上重叠
And so you can...you also have the option if there's multiple cores than multiple threat
所以你可以...如果有多个核心而不是多个威胁，你也可以选择
A thread can run on each core so then you can have true parallelism
线程可以在每个核心上运行，因此你可以拥有真正的并行性
Okay
好的
Okay so like i said threads and processes are similar ideas
好吧，就像我说线程和流程是类似的想法
But in the sense that they each stage kinase and process corresponds to some kind of logical flow
但从某种意义上说，他们每个阶段的激酶和过程都对应于某种逻辑流程
And they can run concurrently with other flows
它们可以与其他流程同时运行
And each is scheduled and contact switched by the kernel
并且每个都是由内核调度和联系人切换的
Okay but they're different because threads share all code and data except their local stacks
好吧但是它们是不同的，因为线程共享除本地堆栈之外的所有代码和数据
And in fact those local stacks although they're each thread has its own it's really just sharing the same stack
事实上，那些本地堆栈虽然它们每个线程都有自己的，但它实际上只是共享相同的堆栈
And so it's really the same portion of the virtual address space
所以它实际上是虚拟地址空间的相同部分
It's just that each thread is assigned its own part of that stack
只是为每个线程分配了自己的堆栈部分
Okay so even though threads have their own individual stacks
好的，即使线程有自己独立的堆栈
Since it's all part of the same virtual address space
因为它是同一虚拟地址空间的所有部分
A thread can access the stack of any other thread
线程可以访问任何其他线程的堆栈
If it's and that's not a good thing to do but it's possible
如果它是，这不是一件好事，但它是可能的
Okay so processes don't share any of the state
好的，所以流程不共享任何州
Right they have their own private address spaces
他们有自己的私人地址空间
And threads are less expensive than processes
线程比流程便宜
It's cheaper to create them
创建它们会更便宜
And the main reason is that there's just less context associated with the thread than there is as a process
主要原因是与线程关联的上下文数量少于作为进程的上下文
And so on our system when we measure
当我们测量时，我们的系统等等
A bunch of we just create in and wait for a bunch of creative process wait for word process over and over again and measure the time
我们刚刚创建了一堆并等待一堆创作过程一遍又一遍地等待文字处理并测量时间
Turns out to be about twenty thousand cycles to create and
结果是大约两万个周期来创建和
Reap a process about ten thousand cycles to create an reapeth thread
获得一个大约一万个周期的进程来创建一个reapeth线程
So that the kernel provides threads to us using an interface called the pthreads  posix threads
这样内核就可以使用名为pthreads posix线程的接口为我们提供线程
So this is a fairly recent standard that all linux,unix systems and windows macintosh
所以这是一个相当新的标准，所有linux，unix系统和windows macintosh
So every this is a sort of standard posix standard for manipulating threads
因此，每一个都是一种用于操纵线程的标准posix标准
And so you can do things like create and reap threads
所以你可以做一些事情，比如创建和收获线程
So there's this is sort of sort of like fork
所以这有点像叉子
And this is sort of like weight but not quite because it doesn't create
这有点像重量但不完全是因为它没有创造
There's no hierarchy associated with these
没有与这些相关的层次结构
You can you could just like get pit you can retain there's a function to get your thread id
你可以只想得到坑，你可以保留一个函数来获取你的线程ID
You can kill threads so one thread can kill another thread
你可以杀死线程，以便一个线程可以杀死另一个线程
A thread there's a there's a function to exit a thread
一个线程有一个退出线程的函数
The normal exit system call terminates all the threads
正常的退出系统调用终止所有线程
And return is similar to pthread_exit in the sense that just terminates the current thread that calls it
返回类似于pthread_exit，只是终止调用它的当前线程
And then there's ways to access synchronize access to shared variables
然后有办法访问共享变量的同步访问
Which we'll look at on thursday more detail
我们将在周四详细介绍
Okay so here's the pthreads hello world program
好的，这就是pthreads的 hello world program
You know your k&r book the the c reference manual
你知道你的k＆r预订了c参考手册
The very first thing that it does is it shows you how to write the simplest possible c program called
它首先要做的是它向你展示如何编写最简单的c程序
So the famous hello world program
就是著名的hello程序
So that goes all the way back to like 1978 when k&r book was first written
因此，当k＆r书籍首次编写时，这就像1978年一样
But that's caught on
但那已经流行起来了
And whenever we like learn a new language or we learn a new concept
每当我们喜欢学习新语言或学习新概念时
We always write the hello world program for that concept
我们总是为这个概念编写hello world程序
So the hello world program for threads this is a simplest threads program that i can think of
所以线程的hello world程序这是我能想到的最简单的线程程序
So i call it the hello world program for threads
所以我把它称为线程的hello world程序
So this program defines a function
所以这个程序定义了一个函数
So court by in posix
因此，在posix法院
A thread is actually executed by executing the the code and a function called the thread routine
线程实际上是通过执行代码和一个称为线程例程的函数来执行的
Okay and posix imposes
posix强加
This thread routine takes a generic pointer as an argument optional generic pointer
此线程例程将通用指针作为参数可选通用指针
And it returns a generic pointer
它返回一个通用指针
Okay so anytime if you want to pass anything to a thread you somehow got to pack up all that data into a single object
好的，所以如果你想将任何东西传递给一个线程，你就可以将所有数据打包成一个对象
Then you can take an address up
然后你可以拿一个地址
But it's it you can see that this is extremely general-purpose
但是你可以看到这是非常通用的
So our hello world program creates a thread by calling pthread create
所以我们的hello world程序通过调用pthread_create来创建一个线程
And we say instead of a child we call this a peer thread
而且我们说的不是孩子而是我们称之为同伴线程
Okay so that there's no parent-child relationship any threads can threads can reap other threads
好的，所以没有父子关系，任何线程都可以让线程获得其他线程
Whether they created those threads or not
他们是否创建了这些线程
Okay so you don't have the strict parent-child hierarchy
好的，所以你没有严格的父子层次结构
Pthread_create creates a thread that executes the thread routine in this third argument
Pthread_create创建一个线程，在第三个参数中执行线程例程
And returns the thread id of that thread in the address and the integer pointed at by the first argument
并返回地址中该线程的线程ID和第一个参数指向的整数
The second argument is set up there's ways to set attributes of threads
第二个参数设置有设置线程属性的方法
That are beyond the scope of this course and will always just have those no
这超出了本课程的范围，并且总是只有那些没有
And then that this fourth argument is the optional argument that you want to pass to your thread routine
然后，第四个参数是你想要传递给线程例程的可选参数
Okay so in this case we're saying call the thread routine
好的，所以在这种情况下我们说调用线程例程
That's called thread with no arguments
这被称为没有参数的线程
And then our thread routine just prints out hello world
然后我们的线程例程就会打印出hello world
And then it returns in this case it doesn't return anything so it returns no
然后它返回在这种情况下它不返回任何东西，所以它返回否
But if we wanted to return something to the calling program
但是如果我们想要将某些东西归还给调用程序
We could have returned something a pointer to some generic object okay
我们本可以返回指向某个通用对象的指针
Okay so the thread id the thread attributes are null that the thread routine the thread arguments are void *p
好的，线程属性的线程id为null，线程参数为void * p的线程例程
And the return value is a void double
并且返回值是void double
So it's a pointer to the pointer that you want to return
所以它是指向要返回的指针的指针
Okay all right so let's look at what happens when we execute hello world
好吧好吧让我们来看看当我们执行hello world时会发生什么
So the main thread runs for a while
所以主线程运行了一段时间
Then it calls pthread_create
然后它调用pthread_create
Which creates the peer thread which now is a concurrent flow that's running
这创建了对等线程，该线程现在是正在运行的并发流
Once the pthread create returns then we're running two concurrent flows or running the main thread
一旦pthread创建返回，那么我们将运行两个并发流或运行主线程
And we're running the peer thread
我们正在运行对等线程
And so in this case hello world waits for the peer thread to finish by calling pthread_join
所以在这种情况下，hello world通过调用pthread_join等待对等线程完成
The peer thread after the calls it's printf it returns
调用它之后的对等线程返回它的printf
No which terminates the thread at that point the pthread_join returns and the main thread continues
否则在该点终止线程pthread_join返回并且主线程继续
Okay so using these create this create function how would we write a thread based concurrent echo server
好的，所以使用这些创建这个创建函数我们如何编写基于线程的并发echo服务器
And again it's very similar to the way we did it with the process based design
而且它与我们使用基于流程的设计的方式非常相似
So we call we acquire a listening descriptor by calling open_listenfd function just as before
所以我们称之为通过像以前一样调用open_listenfd函数来获取监听描述符
And then inside this infinite server loop
然后在这个无限的服务器循环里面
We get the size of the
我们得到的大小
We get the size of the clientaddr struct so which is going to be a large enough to fit any address
我们得到clientaddr结构的大小，这个大小足以适合任何地址
And then we malloc space for the connected file descriptor
然后我们将malloc空间用于连接的文件描述符
So we're making a one integer sized portion of dynamic storage for this connected descriptor
因此，我们为此连接的描述符创建一个整数大小的动态存储部分
That were that we're going to get back from accept
那就是我们要从接受中恢复过来
And we're going to...this is actually really important to avoid a nasty race condition
而且我们要......这对于避免恶劣的竞争条件实际上非常重要
They'll show you in a second
他们会在一秒钟内告诉你
So now we call except with our listening descriptor and clientaddr and clientlen just like before
所以现在我们调用除了我们的侦听描述符和clientaddr以及clientlen之前就像之前一样
And except returns the connected descriptor and then we dereference this connected descriptor pointer
除了返回连接的描述符，然后我们取消引用这个连接的描述符指针
And so and store that the value returned by except in this location in the heap
所以并将除了在此位置之外返回的值存储在堆中
And then we call pthread_create
然后我们调用pthread_create
By giving it the name of our thread routine
通过给它我们的线程例程的名称
Which in this case is just simply a function we defined in our program called thread
在这种情况下，这只是我们在程序中定义的一个函数，称为thread
And the pointer to the connected file descriptor
以及指向连接文件描述符的指针
Okay now a client which a client which a thread routine then will use to interact with the client
现在好了一个客户端，一个客户端，然后一个线程例程将用来与客户端进行交互
Okay so the thread routine dereferences the argument a member is a pointer to a connected file descriptor
好的，所以线程例程取消引用参数，成员是指向连接文件描述符的指针
So it dereferences that pointer to get the to get the actual integer connected descriptor
所以它取消引用指针来获取实际的整数连接描述符
And then it detaches the thread
然后它分离线程
So by default threads
所以默认是线程
Threads run an independent and attached mode
线程运行独立的附加模式
So they can be you know they can be joined by other threads and they can be killed by other threads
所以他们可以知道他们可以被其他线程加入，他们可以被其他线程杀死
But
但
By default if
默认情况下是
It's similar when threads are running in unattached mode or undetected mode
当线程以未连接模式或未检测模式运行时，它类似
That when they die they have wait by a join function to acquire those resources
当他们死亡时，他们等待加入功能来获取这些资源
But if we detach a thread then it can't be joined by any threads but when it dies the kernel will automatically
但是如果我们分离一个线程然后它就不能被任何线程连接，但是当它死掉时，内核会自动进行
Restore the the resources associated with that thread
恢复与该线程关联的资源
So in this case we're going to just detach this thread
所以在这种情况下，我们将分离这个线程
So we're not to worry about reaping it when it finishes
所以我们不要担心它完成后会收获它
And then we're going to free this memory that was malloc
然后我们将释放这个malloc内存
So this is important we have to free this memory that was malloc by the main thread in order to avoid a memory leak
因此，重要的是我们必须释放主线程为malloc的内存，以避免内存泄漏
And then we call echo function so we interact with the the echo client until the echo clients finished
然后我们调用echo函数，以便我们与echo客户端进行交互，直到echo客户端完成
And then we close this descriptor again to avoid a potentially fatal memory leak
然后我们再次关闭此描述符以避免可能致命的内存泄漏
So this thread based education model is very similar to the execution model that we saw with processes
因此，这种基于线程的教育模型与我们在流程中看到的执行模型非常相似
So we have a list of a main thread that's listening for connection requests
所以我们有一个正在监听连接请求的主线程列表
They were waiting for connection requests via accept
他们正在通过接受等待连接请求
And then we have for each client we have a peer thread that interacts with that client
然后我们为每个客户端提供了一个与该客户端交互的对等线程
Using the connected descriptor that was passed in when we created the thread
使用我们创建线程时传入的连接描述符
And then each thread has its own since it has its own stack it has separate space for its local variables
然后每个线程都有自己的，因为它有自己的堆栈，它的局部变量有独立的空间
And this is really the powerful thing about threads
这真的是关于线程的强大功能
Now we can with these things they by declaring these local variables we can
现在我们可以通过声明这些局部变量来解决这些问题
We can create threads that won't interact with each other
我们可以创建不会相互交互的线程
It won't and can run independently yes
它不会也可以独立运行是的
[student speaking]
I guess yeah the question is there any time you wouldn't want to run detached
我想是的，问题是，任何时候你都不想分开运行
So when you run detached you give up the power to kill other threads so
所以当你分开运行时，你就放弃了杀死其他线程的能力
So i don't know if you it's hard to it's hard to come up with good example right that
所以我不知道你是否很难找到正确的例子
But if you wanted the ability to be able to terminate other threads
但是如果你想要能够终止其他线程的能力
You know maybe if you had
你知道也许你有
Maybe if you were running a pool of like worker threads
也许如果你正在运行类似工作线程的池
And at some point
在某些时候
At some point if i mean i guess you can imagine a scenario where suppose you're running a pool of worker threads
在某些时候，如果我的意思是我猜你可以想象一个场景，假设你正在运行一个工作线程池
You give them all jobs to do the first one that finishes you take the result
你给他们所有工作做第一个完成你取得结果的工作
And you don't need the results from the other threads
而且你不需要其他线程的结果
So you might just want to kill those threads
所以你可能只想杀死那些线程
But it's yeah it's hard to come up with a really compelling reason
但是，是的，很难找到一个非常令人信服的理由
Okay so there's a few things to think about when you're writing thread based servers
好吧，当你编写基于线程的服务器时，需要考虑一些事项
So the first is that yet you need to run detach to avoid potential memory leaks
所以首先是你需要运行分离以避免潜在的内存泄漏
I'm sorry i forgot this word so it the opposite of detached is joinable
对不起，我忘记了这个词，所以它与分离的相反是可以加入的
And so joinable threads like i mentioned can be reaped and killed by other threads detached threads cannot
所以像我提到的可连接线程可以通过其他线程分离线程无法获取和杀死
And their resources are automatically claimed on termination
他们的资源在终止时自动声明
So the default states joinable and you have to use this detach function call to make the thread detached
所以默认状态是可连接的，你必须使用这个分离函数调用来分离线程
The biggest issue with threads though
虽然线程最大的问题
Like the beautiful thing about threads is that you're sharing the same global address space
就像线程的美妙之处在于，你正在共享相同的全局地址空间
So it's very easy to share data structures you know if you had multiple threads
因此，如果你有多个线程，那么共享你知道的数据结构非常容易
If you had a web server a concurrent web server that was built with multiple threads be very easy to implement a cache
如果你有一个Web服务器，使用多个线程构建的并发Web服务器很容易实现缓存
All the threads could use right because they're all sharing that same virtual address space
所有线程都可以正确使用，因为它们都共享相同的虚拟地址空间
But the thing that makes threads so nice
但是让线程如此美妙的东西
This ease the ease with which you can share resources  is also the thing that makes them very tricky to deal with
这样可以轻松轻松地共享资源，这也使得处理它们变得非常棘手
So as soon as just like we saw with our shell lab handlers
就像我们看到我们的shell实验室处理程序一样
You know as soon as you have multiple flows accessing shared resources you have to be very careful
你知道，只要你有多个流访问共享资源，你就必须非常小心
It's very easy to make mistakes
犯错很容易
And it's very easy to or it's possible to to share resources in unexpected and unintended ways
并且很容易或者有可能以意想不到的方式共享资源
For example if one thread passes the address of a local variable on its stack to another thread
例如，如果一个线程将其堆栈上的局部变量的地址传递给另一个线程
Then now that the called thread now has access to the callers thread
然后现在被调用的线程现在可以访问调用者线程
And there's nothing to prevent that called thread from manipulating local variables on the caller stack
并且没有什么可以阻止被调用的线程操纵调用者堆栈上的局部变量
You know that would be a very bad thing to do
你知道这将是一件非常糟糕的事情
But it's possible you might forget,you know you might forget that the variable you're passing is a local variable, not a global
但是你可能会忘记，你知道你可能会忘记你传递的变量是局部变量，而不是全局变量
Okay and a really bad mistake
好吧，这是一个非常糟糕的错误
In our hello...in our echo server example
在我们的问候中...在我们的echo服务器示例中
Notice we were very careful to malloc you space for this
请注意，我们非常小心地为此安排了空间
For this connected file descriptor that we passed into that the peer thread that we are creating
对于我们传入我们正在创建的对等线程的连接文件描述符
Would have been much easier just to pass the address of the connected file descriptor into a peer thread be much easier
将连接文件描述符的地址传递给对等线程会容易得多
But it would also be wrong
但这也是错误的
Can you say why
你能说出原因吗？
Okay let's say right here when we call pthread_create
好的，我们在这里打电话给pthread_create吧
Instead of passing a pointer to a separately allocated region of the heap
而不是将指针传递给堆的单独分配区域
Instead of doing that we just pass the address of the connected file descriptor same thing right
而不是这样做我们只是传递连接文件描述符的地址同样的事情
Okay and then in a thread routine we dereference that pointer to to get the connected file descriptor
好的，然后在一个线程例程中，我们取消引用指向获取连接文件描述符的指针
Okay if we just pass the address of the connected file descriptor
好的，如果我们只传递连接文件描述符的地址
This is real it's really bad,can you say why
这是真的很糟糕，你能说出原因吗？
Yes
是
It does, okay that's true, and why is that
确实如此，这是真的，为什么会这样
[student speaking]
That's yeah that's right so what this is assuming
那是的，这是正确的，所以这是假设
This entered this bypassing the address of this connected file descriptor
这导致绕过此连接文件描述符的地址
We're introducing a race
我们正在引入一场比赛
Okay in the race what we're assuming
在比赛中我们正在假设
That the peer thread will be able to dereference that pointer
对等线程将能够取消引用该指针
Before
之前
The main thread goes back up and gets a new connected file descriptor
主线程返回并获取新的连接文件描述符
Right so what happens what happens
对，所发生的事情发生了什么
Right we can't in a concurrent system,we can't make any assumptions about how the kernel is going to schedule things
对，我们不能在并发系统中，我们不能对内核如何安排事情做出任何假设
Right we saw the same thing with processes
对，我们看到了与流程相同的事情
So what happens if after pthread_create
那么如果在pthread_create之后会发生什么
The main thread runs instead of the peer thread
主线程运行而不是对等线程
Okay so we've passed the
好的，所以我们通过了
We've passed the address of the connected file descriptor for this client
我们已经传递了该客户端的连接文件描述符的地址
That we accepted the connection requests from
我们接受了来自的连接请求
And then before the peer thread can dereference that argument we get a new connected file descriptor
然后在对等线程可以取消引用该参数之前，我们得到一个新的连接文件描述符
Okay
好的
And now the child runs
现在孩子跑了
And it dereferences that descriptor
它解释了描述符
But what it gets now is the descriptor
但它现在得到的是描述符
That's corresponding to the second child not the first child
这相当于第二个孩子而不是第一个孩子
So now we have two threads talking to the same client using the same descriptor
所以现在我们有两个线程使用相同的描述符与同一客户端通信
So do you see them hope
那么你看到他们的希望吗？
So it's very tricky this is like a real subtle this is an example of sort of subtle errors that you can introduce
所以它非常棘手，这就像一个真正的微妙，这是你可以介绍的一些细微错误的例子
Because of this unintended sharing
因为这种无意识的分享
And it's cause the root cause is as you correctly pointed out is that they're both sharing the same memory on the caller stack
这是因为你正确指出的根本原因是它们在调用者堆栈上共享相同的内存
Yes
是
[student speaking]
In this case of what you could do there's another thing you could do you could just pass the descriptor itself
在这种情况下你可以做什么，你可以做的另一件事你可以只传递描述符本身
Okay so you could just cast the descriptor to a generic pointer and just pass that
好吧，你可以将描述符转换为通用指针，然后传递它
And that that's just kind of yucky though that that would work
虽然那会有用，但这有点令人讨厌
Because instead of dereferencing it the child would just use it directly
因为孩子不是解除引用它而是直接使用它
Okay so good that's good
好的，这很好
Okay the
好的
So the really good things with with threads is ease of sharing
因此，线程的真正好处是易于共享
But that sharing also introduces can introduce complications
但是这种分享也会引入并发症
In fact that's we're going to look at ways to sort of control the the sharing
事实上，我们将研究如何控制共享
So that we do...so that we don't get unintended unintended sharing
所以我们这样做......这样我们就不会意外地进行无意识的共享
Okay so to summarize the the approaches to concurrency that
好的，总结一下并发的方法
That we've looked at we have process based concurrency
我们已经看过，我们有基于进程的并发性
So it's hard to share resources but
所以很难分享资源但是
It's easy to avoid unintended sharing so in some ways it's safer and easier to program
很容易避免意外共享，所以在某些方面它更安全，更容易编程
Event based so it's it's very low-level very tedious
基于事件，所以这是非常低级非常乏味
You have to be very careful about how you the granularity of the work that you do in response to events
你必须非常小心你在响应事件时如何处理工作的粒度
But you have total control over scheduling so you can decide which
但是你可以完全控制调度，这样你就可以决定哪一个
Which descriptors you're going to service and in which order it sits since there's a single flow of control
你将要服务的描述符以及它所处的顺序，因为只有一个控制流
You can debug it with a debugger
你可以使用调试器对其进行调试
But it doesn't make use of multi-core so there's a handful of trade-offs there
但它没有使用多核，所以那里有一些权衡
And with thread based systems
并使用基于线程的系统
It's very easy to share resources but that sharing can create problems of its own
共享资源非常容易，但共享可能会产生问题
It's fairly efficient compared to two processors
与两个处理器相比，它相当有效
You don't have much control over the scheduling
你无法控制日程安排
So just like we saw you're not you can't really control which threads get executed in which order
就像我们看到你不是，你无法真正控制哪个线程以哪个顺序执行
And it can be difficult to debug
它可能很难调试
Because there can be races that occur very rarely very infrequently and
因为很少有比赛很少发生
So the probability of sort of creating one of those race conditions is difficult
因此，创造其中一种竞争条件的可能性很难
Okay so that's it for today
好的，这就是今天的情况
Tomorrow we'll look at thread based servers in more detail
明天我们将更详细地介绍基于线程的服务器
And how to write thread based systems efficiently and correctly
以及如何有效和正确地编写基于线程的系统